I check the thermostat,
read the outside air.
It says don't go out there without a proper pair.
I'm zipping up my jacket,
putting gloves on my hand.
Preparing for the freeze that grips this northern land.
But I hear the click-clack coming down the hall.
Like she's stepping off the sand right past the garden wall.
Ooh.
I don't even ask her,
I already know.
She's got a secret summer in the middle of the snow.
She says,
"I need my freedom,
need to feel the floor."
Then she grabs her heavy coat and heads right for the door.
She's walking on the zero-degree beach.
The comfort of that plastic,
nothing else can reach.
She's walking on the zero-degree beach.
A beautiful stubborn habit that the cold can't teach.
No matter if it's autumn or a January sleet.
She's got the only summer that exists beneath her feet.
My quirky queen in her flip-flops all year long.
We went to a wedding,
the venue was so grand.
White gloves and polished shoes across the marble land.
She looked like a million bucks,
every hair was in place.
Except for that telltale sign of her personal space.
When she kicked off her heels just an hour after the dance.
And swapped in the cheap sandals with an affectionate glance.
Said,
"These are the true me,
this is how I thrive.
The only person keeping California alive."
Other people stare,
they give a little look.
But they don't know the comfort that she's found inside that hook.
They don't know the story,
the dedication,
the pieces.
Got her priorities and they're never gonna see.
She's walking on the zero-degree beach.
The comfort of that plastic,
nothing else can reach.
She's walking on the zero-degree beach.
A beautiful stubborn habit that the cold can't teach.
No matter if it's autumn or a January sleet.
She's got the only summer that exists beneath her feet.
My quirky queen in her flip-flops all year long.
It's just a little thing I know,
an insignificant trait.
But it's one of those small wonders that I celebrate.
You found the perfect life hack,
the ultimate release.
You choose your own weather,
you choose your own peace.
All year long.
Ooh.
A zero-degree beach.
Yeah,
all year long.
Ooh.